Sascha Zahra Vernanda | Bachelor of Law

Surabaya, Indonesia / 0895403877208 / saschaazahra@gmail.com / http://www.linkedin.com/in/saschazahra

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

I recently graduated from Universitas Pembangunan Nasional "Veteran" Jawa Timur and landed my first job before graduated on February, 2024. My interpersonal skills allow me to collaborate effectively in teams and engage with individuals from various backgrounds. Consistency, perseverance, and teamwork are foundational traits that define my character. I am highly driven to continually enhance my existing skills and enthusiastically embrace opportunities for learning and growth.

Interest: legal officer, legal counsel, legal department, compliance specialist, contract specialist, corporate lawyer.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Research Competition "LPPM" Program UPN "Veteran" Jawa Timur Awardee: "Optimalisasi Pendampingan Mediasi Sebagai Perwujudan Penyelesaian Sengketa yang Berkeadilan melalui Aplikasi: Ayo Mediasi" PKPA (Pendidikan Khusus Profesi Advokat) Scholarship Awardee on FHP Law School May 2024

March 2024

Masters UPN "Veteran" Jawa Timur Scholarship Awardee (master of law)

February 2024 - Present

Top Graduate: Highest Grade Point Average (GPA)

February 2024

EDUCATION

Universitas Pembangunan Nasional "Veteran" Jawa Timur Law, Faculty of Law (GPA: 3.87/4.00) (Study Period: 4 months 3 years)

2020 - 2024

- Bachelor Thesis: Prosedur pemberian bantuan hukum non litigasi Terhadap Penagihan Piutang Perusahaan BUMN PT Surabaya Industrial Estate Rungkut (SIER) Pada kejaksaan negeri Surabaya.
- Practical Work: Perlindungan Hukum Terhadap PT Surabaya Industrial Estate Rungkut (SIER) Selaku BUMN Akibat Tidak Terdaftar Dalam Daftar Piutang Perusahaan Pailit (Studi Kasus Pada Kejaksaan Negeri Surabaya).

WORK EXPERIENCES & INTERN EXPERIENCES

Kejaksaan Republik Indonesia - Kota Surabaya **Legal Staff**

February 2024 - Present

- Compiling a resume office meetings and organize supporting documents: contract document, land certificate (SHM, SHGB, Hak Pakai, etc).
- Drafting legal opinion and case progress report by analizing and comparing fact and legal basis.
- Taking inventory of incoming case admins and understand the legal regulations for each incoming problem.

Kejaksaan Republik Indonesia - Kota Surabaya Legal Internship

February - June 2023

- Compiling a resume office meetings and organizing documents from each case.
- Analyse the facts and legal basis in each incoming case.
- Taking inventory of incoming case admins and understand the legal regulations for each incoming problem.

Narasi TV **Creative Internship**

September - December 2021

- Developing soft skills by producing content on NARASI TV honed me in the fields of critical thinking, research, video editing, graphic design, team work and time management.
- Responsible for 7content/every week to posting on NARASI TV social media

ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCES & VOLUNTEERS EXPERIENCES

Badan Eksekutif Mahasiswa at UPN Veteran Jawa Timur Staff at Department of external relations ministry of communication

2021 - 2022

- Establish relationships with relevant stakeholders, through various media
- Become a tiktok PIC TikTok BEM by managing all content and related
- Create creative content for social media BEM

Komunitas Peradilan Semu Bela Negara at Universitas Pembangunan Nasional "Veteran" Jawa Timur (UPNVJATIM)

2020 - 2021

Riset staff Mooting

- Update information related to regulations regarding about law.
- Human resource development to hold events to increase law-related knowledge

Public Discussion "Tax Goes to Millenials: UU Cipta Kerja Klaster Perpajakan"

May - June 2021

Head of Program Division

- Lead the event division to classify job descriptions with the team and resolve existing problems related to the
- Specify run down, terms of reference, regulation and time keeper for the event also choosing Master of Ceremony (MC) to guide the whole section of event.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Ms. Office (Ms. Word, Ms. Excel, Ms. PowerPoint) / Intermediate
- Google (Google Collaboratory, Google Docs, Google Spreadsheets, Google Slides) / Intermediate
- Canva

CERTIFICATION

- TOEFL ITP Score: 570 on April, 08 2024
- **PKPA** (Pendidikan Khusus Profesi Advokat) on April, 06 2024

SOFT SKILLS

- Leadership
- Critical Thinking
- Analyzing
- Public Speaking
- Teamwork
- Design skill
- Public Relation
- Communication skill
- Problem solving Content Creator
- **Content Writing**